Okay. So, we've learned a little about factor models.
Ok我们大致了解了因子模型
So, how are they used in practice?
那么如何运用因子模型呢？
It might not be what you expect.
可能与你的预期不同
Most practitioners don't use factor models to explicitly model asset returns.
大多数从业者并不使用因子模型明确对资产收益率建模
Factor modeling has a long history in academic research,
因子建模在学术研究领域有很久的研究历史
and some of these methods were used in the past to explicitly model returns time series.
过去人们会使用某些方法明确对收益率时间序列建模
But when devising and testing trading strategies,
但是在设计和测试交易策略时
the models are typically used slightly differently.
这些模型的用法通常有所不同
We've seen the equations for returns and for risk in terms of factors.
我们见过用因子表示的收益率和风险方程
One key goal is that we want to be able to use
一个关键目标是
these expressions in a portfolio optimization problem.
能够在投资组合优化问题中使用这些表达式
Now, let me tell you about a couple of simplifications that quants make at this point.
下面介绍下量化分析师在此阶段会采取的几个优化
Let's take the matrix of factor exposures.
看看因子暴露度矩阵
As we've said, a value in this matrix represents
之前提到 这个矩阵中的值表示
the sensitivity of an individual asset to a specific factor return.
单个资产对特定因子收益的敏感程度
A portfolio with weights x has a portfolio factor exposure of B transpose x.
权重为 x 的投资组合的因子暴露度为 B^Tx
Now, let's introduce a new idea.
下面介绍一个新的概念
Let's say we think there are actually two types of factors.
假设我们认为有两种因子
One type of factor is predictive of the mean of the distribution of returns.
一种因子可以预测收益率分布的均值
The other type is predictive of the variance of the distribution, but not of the mean.
另一种因子可以预测分布的方差 而不是均值
The first describes our alpha factors,
第一种因子描述的是 alpha 因子
while the second describes our risk factors.
第二种因子描述的是风险因子
We'd rather our portfolio be minimally exposed to risk factors.
我们希望投资组合尽量避免暴露于风险因子
The drivers of volatility.
即波动性的推动因素
We can try to make this happen by placing constraints on
我们可以向 B^Tx 施加约束条件
B transpose x that only apply to factors that we think are drivers of volatility.
并且仅针对我们认为对波动性有推动的因子
We do this typically in the constraints section of the optimization problem.
我们通常在优化问题的约束部分这么做
This will specifically reduce the exposure of our portfolio to these risk factors.
这样通常会降低投资组合对风险因子的暴露度
However, we don't constrain the factors that are drivers of mean returns.
但是 我们不对推动均值收益率的因子加以约束
So, we drop them from B.
所以从 B 中删除它们
Hence, you can think of B now as the risk factor loading matrix only.
现在可以将 B 看作仅包含风险因子的矩阵
The alpha factors aren't kept in here because we're not
没有保留 alpha 因子
going to constrain them the way we do with the risk factors.
因为我们不会像对待风险因子那样约束 alpha 因子
What about F and S. We think about F as
那么 F 和 S 呢
the covariance matrix of factor returns that have
我们将 F 看作对各个股票的方差影响很大的
large impact on variance across all stocks,
因子收益率的协方差矩阵
and S as the variance that's left over.
并将 S 看作剩下的方差
In fact, we define risk factors precisely as
实际上 我们将风险因子明确定义为
factors that have large impact on variance across all stocks.
对各个股票的方差影响很大的因子
So, we include only the risk factors in F. Anything that's left over,
所以我们在 F 中仅包含风险因子
like variance from the alpha factors we took out and everything we can't explain,
拿出来的 alpha 因子方差和无法解释的部分
is accounted for in S. We can use F and S together to constrain portfolio risk.
等剩下的一切都放入 S 中 我们同时用 F 和 S 约束投资组合风险
The key takeaway here though is that, in practice,
知识要点是 在实践中
B and F explicitly contain only information about risk factors.
B 和 F 仅包含关于风险因子的信息
S says nothing explicitly about alpha.
S 没有明确包含关于 alpha 的信息
Practitioners will usually buy F, S,
从业者通常以付费的方式
and B from a commercial provider,
从商业提供方那获取 F S 和 B
and now we can see why that is sufficient.
现在我们明白为何知道这些就足够了
We typically don't mix our alphas and risk factors.
我们通常不会将 alpha 和风险因子混合到一起
What about the alpha factors we took out from B?
那么从 B 中拿走的 alpha 因子呢？
We are left with some number of alpha factors which are values per stock per factor.
还有一些 alpha 因子 它们的值因股票和因子而不同
What do we do with those?
如何处理这些 alpha 因子？
This is where the creation of the objective function and optimization comes in.
这时候就要用到优化问题中的目标函数了
We need to combine these into a single vector,
我们需要将它们组合成一个向量
which we will do in later projects,
我们会在后面的项目中创建这个向量
and optimize our resulting weight to these.
并优化生成的权重